Many oppose workplace surveillance, because of the inherent dehumanizing effect it has and the relentless pressure it brings.
许多人反对职场监控，原因是它本身就会产生非人化的影响，还会带来无休无止的压力。
But it’s on the rise around the world as firms look to become more efficient by squeezing more productivity from their workers.
但在世界各地，职场监控正日益增多，因为企业希望通过从员工身上榨取更多生产力来提高效率。
More than half of companies with over $750m in annual revenue used “non-traditional” monitoring techniques on staff last year.
去年，年收入超过7.5亿美元的公司中，有一半以上对员工使用了“非传统”的监控手段。
Monitoring employee performance gives firms the ability to assess how their staff are performing and interacting, which can be good for both the firm and employees themselves.
监控员工的工作表现，能让企业评估员工表现如何、互动情况怎样，这对企业和员工自身都可能有好处。
A growing number of analytics companies offer this service.
越来越多的数据分析公司提供这种服务。
They gather “data exhaust” left by employees’ email and instant messaging apps, and use name badges equipped with radio-frequency identification devices and microphones.
这些公司收集员工的电子邮件和即时通讯应用留下的“数据废气”，还使用装有射频识别装置和麦克风的胸牌。
These can check how much time you spend talking, your volume and tone of voice, and even whether you dominate conversations.
这些设备能检测你说话的时长、音量和语气，甚至能检测你是否在谈话中占据主导。
While this may sound intrusive, exponents argue that it can also protect employees against bullying and sexual harassment.
虽然这听起来可能有侵犯隐私之嫌，但支持者认为，它也能保护员工免受欺凌和性骚扰。
Some of this data analysis can produce unexpected results.
这类数据分析中，有一些能得出意想不到的结果。
For example, it was found that people who sat at 12-person lunch tables tended to interact, share ideas more and outperform those who regularly sat at four-person tables, a fact that would probably have gone undetected without such data analysis.
例如，人们发现，午餐时坐12人桌的人往往互动更多、分享想法更多，表现也胜过经常坐4人桌的人；要是没有这样的数据分析，这一事实很可能就无人察觉。
Over the last few years a Stockholm co-working space called Epicenter has gone much further and holds popular “chipping parties”, where people can have microchips implanted in their hands.
过去几年里，斯德哥尔摩一家名为Epicenter的共享办公空间走得要远得多，它举办的“植芯派对”很受欢迎，人们可以在派对上把微芯片植入手中。
They can use the implants to access electronically controlled doors, or monitor how typing speed correlates with heart rate.
这些人可以利用植入的芯片进出电控门，或者监测打字速度与心率之间有怎样的关联。
Implanted chips may seem extreme, but it is a relatively small step from ID cards and biometrics to such devices.
植入的芯片或许显得很极端，但从身份识别卡和生物识别技术迈向这类装置，这一步相对较小。
As long as such schemes are voluntary, there will probably be a growing number of convenience-oriented uses so that a substantial number of workers will opt to have a chip inserted.
只要这类计划是自愿参加的，以便利为导向的用途很可能会越来越多，从而会有相当多的员工选择植入芯片。
But if implanted chips are used to reduce slack time or rest breaks, that could prove to be detrimental.
但如果用植入的芯片来减少空闲时间或工间休息，结果就可能是有害的。
And if surveillance tools take away autonomy, that’s when they prove most unpopular.
而如果监控工具剥夺了自主权，那就最不得人心了。
A lot depends on how such monitoring initiatives are communicated, and this could prevent possible revolts being staged.
很多事情都取决于如何传达这类监控举措，传达得好，或许就能防止员工可能发动的反抗。
If bosses don’t communicate effectively, employees assume the worst.
如果老板不能有效沟通，员工就会往最坏处想。
But if they’re open about the information they’re collecting and what they’re doing with it, research suggests 46% of employees are generally okay with it.
但研究表明，如果老板坦诚说明自己在收集哪些信息、用这些信息做什么，46%的员工大体上可以接受。
Although many such monitoring schemes use anonymised data and participation is voluntary, many staffers remain sceptical and fear an erosion of their civil liberties.
尽管许多这类监控计划使用的是匿名化数据，参与也出于自愿，但许多员工仍然心存怀疑，担心自己的公民自由受到侵蚀。
So workplace surveillance could be empowering for staff and useful for companies looking to become more efficient and profitable.
因此，职场监控可能既为员工赋能，又对希望提高效率、增加盈利的公司有用。
But implemented in the wrong way, it could also become an unpopular tool of oppression that proves counterproductive.
但如果实施方式不当，职场监控也可能沦为一种不得人心的压迫工具，结果适得其反。